# Shivendra Saurav, Frontend Developer



Experienced in using React, Vite and Next frameworks. Led the development of a project for a coffee producer that was deemed "gold standard" by the client. well acquainted with the aspects of UI/UX design and responsible for the design of all projects in the portfolio showcase.

#### Experience

#### Senior Software Engineer - LTIMindtree, Bengaluru

May 2022 - Present

- Gathered requirements and concerns from an external client and prepared sprint plans, bot flows, and other documentation.
- Used design specifications and documentation to complete the development of processes within the given timeline.
- Reported concerns and bugs as incidents to the team lead and solved them effectively.

#### Trainee Engineer - LTIMindtree, Chennai

July 2021 - April 2022

- Provided support to external clients who utilised our services and were using the automation anywhere platform.
- Help with the development and production of bot runners on the Automation Anywhere platform.
- Collection and reporting of status for each process at the end of the day, and creating incidents for processes that failed to further look into the issues that may have led to the failure.

#### Education

### Bachelor of Technology - REVA University, Bengaluru

July 2017 - July 2021

- Graduated with a specialisation in computer science and engineering.
- Core member and Mentor at Google Developers Student Club, REVA University.
- Organised and Participated in many events as member of Hackathon Club, REVA University.

#### Certifications

## Full Stack Web Development with React - Coursera

April 2020 - June 2020

- Course by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.
- Focuses on building Full Stack Web Applications using the MERN Stack.

## UI/UX Design - Coursera

January 2020 - March 2020

- Course by The California Institute of the Arts.
- Focuses on building intuitive designs for Mobile and Desktop using The Design Thinking Process.

## Skills

HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React, Node JS, Express JS, Flutter, Python, MySQL,

#### Adept In

Web Development, Cross Platform PWAs, Single Page Applications, Responsive Design, UI/UX Design, API Requests,

#### Links

GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio